對唔住，我嚟遲咗，因為我喺隔籬開緊房屋委委員會嘅個會嚇。噉我哋誒呢個會誒誒成員又係有一二三四五六有六位喺度嘅。我哋而家就第一個誒誒，就一件事咧，要誒選呢個主席啊。我想大家。
誒係啊！接受你講咗提名，我先要舉手。係提名有冇提名喺度嚇？想提名啊，吳亮星議員。係啊，吳亮星議員接唔接受啊？嚇，我仲和有冇和議嚇？
阿石禮謙和餘霞，阿阿梁星霞，有冇其他？有冇其他嘅誒提名啊？
冇，我理他冇。
冇啊嚇！誒，兩先麻煩你嚇。
啊！誒，梁家傑，我哋啱選咗呢個主席嚇。
我知道你有啲弊弊地噉啊，所以問一問你，話聲畀你聽，你可以選副主席嘅，唔使。
都有。
整咗啲嘢。
唔該。
而家選咗噉，使唔使選副主席？好啊，你先。誒，唔使選副主席，我哋就可以。唔使選副主席，係係。
我諗有冇需要選副主席啊？
冇嘢需要啊。O K，噉我哋又請官員可以入嚟。
你可以就請咗政府介紹先，亦或者係決定就翻呢條誒呢三個附屬法例。
姚志進。
同埋咧，最後咧就。
咁最後一間就一路去。
佢今日。
咧就做到一萬八。
係，朝早。
好歡迎呢個今日出席嘅。
啊！政府方面有。
以下幾位啊！
就係香港金融管理局。
誒先講財經事務及副務首席。
助理秘書長係廖俊傑先生。
啊！有香港金融管理局助理總裁。
簡家蘭女士。
誒。
金融管理局誒。
銀行政策主管朱少雄先生。
有金融管理局嘅高級經理邱美英女士。
你個。
律政司高級助理法。
炒熱均勻。
林少仲先生律政司政府律師吳文。
俊先生以及。
律政司、政府律師。
吳榮敏女士。
噉就我先歡迎各位參加，我哋誒今日就係呢一個三條附屬例嘅。
誒，我哋嘅小組委員會咧就進行呢個審議工作。首先咧，就我哋先邀請政府官員方面咧，就簡介一下以下嗰三項嘅附屬法例裏邊嘅內容。
誒政府方面咪減少。
yes.
主席，這三項補充立法關聯到銀行規管是相連的。兩項較短的條文將生效《銀行修正條例》2012，讓貨幣局可以訂定規則，規範新的巴塞爾三資本標準，並加入多邊。
投資保證局進入多邊發展銀行名單，被多邊發展銀行認可。
Following a similar move by the Basel Committee to recognise MIGA as a multilateral development bank for the purpose of reducing banks' capital charges on exposures to it.
第三件附屬立法是更實質的，並設出一套修訂銀行資本規則的修訂，以引入新的巴薩爾三最低資本比率和新的巴薩爾三資本定義，並擴展風險覆蓋範圍的監管資本框架，以應對對方信用風險。
跟著，巴爾茲爾三。
Basel III, as members are no doubt aware, is an international standard which draws upon the lessons of the recent global financial crisis to build more resilient banks through higher and better quality capital.
The banking industry were consulted globally during the course of the development of Basel III, and as far as the local implementation of Basel III is concerned, the banking industry in Hong Kong has been consulted on several occasions over the past year.
巴爾茲爾委員會設置了一個實施時間表，以引進巴爾茲爾三，這延續了六年，直到2019年，以使逐步引入巴爾茲爾三要求，強化銀行的資本和流動性狀況，而不必對銀行的貸款和信貸中介業務造成過度幹擾。
Under the Basel Committee timetable, the first phase of Basel III implementation—the new minimum risk-weighted ratios, the new definition of capital, and the counterparty credit risk enhancements—is due to begin on 1 January 2013. And accordingly, the banking capital amendment rules before members prescribe that date as their date.
commencement.
There will be further rules and rule amendments tabled before the Legislative Council over the next few years until 2019 to introduce the subsequent phases of the Basel III framework in line with the Basel Committee timetable.
It is the stated intention of the Monetary Authority and the Financial Services and the Treasury Bureau to adopt and follow the Basel Committee timetable. The Monetary Authority is a member of the Basel Committee. We were invited to join in 2009, and it seems to us appropriate to comply with the committee's standards, including timeline, in circumstances where there are no compelling reasons not.
要。
我們 not proposing early adoption of standards, nor to gold plate the standards. Our rules are therefore substantively in alignment with Basel III.
There are a couple of deductions which are to be made in the calculation of the regulatory capital base, where we are more stringent than Basel III. But our banks already make these deductions under our existing capital framework, so it will not be a change for them. And we consider the existing approach to be preferable to that under Basel III in the light of local circumstances.
The Financial Stability Board has recently noted that it is crucial that all jurisdictions redouble their efforts to pass legislation that is consistent with the Basel III framework by the agreed deadline.
巴爾茲委員會正在監察其成員司法管轄區採納巴爾茲三，並定期向G20報告此事。
巴爾茲委員會也這一年開始了一個評估計劃，一種形式的同行審查，藉此每個管轄區的規例被評估其實際的遵守巴爾茲三項要求的程度。
所以，它不是説，是的，我們有巴塞爾三條規則在位。評估團隊會逐條逐條看，看該司法管轄區的規則是否比巴塞爾三條規則更嚴格。
The reports produced as a result of these assessments will be published on the Basel Committee's website.
Finally, it is probably evident from what I have already said, but the Basel III standards are international minimum standards. Jurisdictions are free to go above the standards, and the approach adopted by other jurisdictions in this regard is something that we will obviously be monitoring. Okay, thank you, Karen.
呃。
政府基本上將嗰個即係少少嘅背景方面提咗一下，咁咧就因為係三條法律都係有相關，噉就誒。
巴蘇菲即係巴塞爾協議三咧，呢個係一個主主要嘅國際性要求。噉啊，我亦都補充下，即係銀行業咧，原則上都會啊，都會按照國際嘅誒慣例做法嘅咧，就會跟從時間表去做嘢。噉啊～
政府方面當然都頭先都強調咗，就唔會提早嘅。嗱，呢點係好重要。我哋亦都唔需要走喺特別喺人哋之前，只不過按照翻佢嘅期限去做。
誒當然包括不定期嘅今誒今日有有一需要定期嘅做出對G二千誒G二。
G二十啊，G二十啊，G二千啊，G二十嘅有關報告咧，呢啲我諗啊，銀行界都係一樣誒，本住呢個跟隨誒國際規定咧就做嘅。咁以下咧，我就想簡單聽聽大家對剛才政府提嘅有關背景同埋有關。
嘅要求方面咧，有冇咩特別意見？請委員提出。係，阿田議員。
Yes, Chairman. Certainly, I mean, if this is an international bank's agreement, Hong Kong will have to abide by it. But I think you mentioned that we're not doing this earlier than other countries.
But I I have the feeling that in a lot of banks in Europe, they are not going to start at 2013. Like you said, it's going to start at 13219 over a period of six years to fully implement the special three.
But are we now trying to do this through the legislation and have it implemented by when? Or are we saying that we have the legislation ready, but we're not going to implement it yet? Are we doing this ahead of schedule of say banks in Spain or Italy because?
The general public feeling is that a lot of those banks are not in good enough shape today on the capital ratio to actually implement the Basel III as agreed.
嗯，A，thank you，Chairman。
The Basel Committee set the timetable, and they set the 1st of January 2013 as the implementation date for the new minimum ratios and the new definition of capital. That has not been changed by the Basel Committee. That remains the timeline. Major Asian jurisdictions such as Japan, Singapore.
Australia and the mainland have already issued their rules, ready to go into effect on 1 January 2013. As have other financial centres such as Switzerland. You are correct that in the EU, they probably due to some competing priorities, they are still discussing what they call.
CRD四，這是他們版本的巴爾茲三。我認為他們生產三種不同的版本。一種由歐盟委員會，一種由歐盟理事會，一種由議會。目前他們在進行所謂的三角談判，即三邊討論，以達成一致。
the language of that CRD IV directive.
I think they were meeting on it on the 23rd, 24th October, and they are due to meet again in November. I mean, we are now into November, so I think it is not unlikely that there will be some delay in Europe. I think the intention is still to get a sort of political agreement.
Agreement on it by the end of this year, but it's difficult to get agreement at the end of this year and then introduce it immediately on the 1st of January. But that is a European issue, with a European problem. The Basel Committee remain committed to the 1st of January 2013.
主席，如果係噉，我就好想問下，本地銀行同國際銀行，或者國際銀行嘅空間。
Let's say Europe. If we have this law enacted in Hong Kong, we will be implementing at the same time for a local bank.
Of Hong Kong versus a subsidiary of, say, a Spanish bank or Italian bank that has a branch that's in business in Hong Kong. If they cannot abide by that, would they be at a disadvantage?
We will local banks that are incorporated here and subsidiaries that are incorporated here of global groups will be subject to the Basel III rules here with effect from the 1st of January. We don't set capital rules for branches. No. So so the branch will be set from its.
我見，我唔 realise到。
and the last question is that.
for the every child on the street. what's what does that mean? Does that mean that the borrowing cost for all businesses?
Whether they are conglomerates or SMEs, it's likely to go up in the sense of the not the high bar but the high bar plus the margin will go up because the banks will have to put more into the capital.
Versus the loan ratio? Well, actually, banks in Hong Kong are already very well capitalised. They already hold buffers in excess of the minimum requirements. So the cost of holding this additional capital is not new to them. The average capital adequacy ratio at the end of June was 15.9%.
with a tier one capital ratio of 13%, and of that tier one ratio, about 89% is common equity tier one. So that gives you a sort of 10% roughly common equity tier one. So they are already in excess of the levels set by by Basel III. Even if that were not the case, the whole idea
The six-year transition period would be to allow banks to move gradually into the standards. So the idea is not to create any sudden increase in banks' capital that would cause them to need to raise charges dramatically.
just just a last supplement question. That means, as far as practically is concerned in Hong Kong, our banks are well capitalised. So if we implement them in two thousand and thirteen, it will not really affect, especially for general businesses, the cost of borrowing for the general business.
Sector certainly not through this this regulation. What other factors the banks may take into account?
唔該。
啊，先呢個。
好，多謝主席。我想問問咧，即係。
頭先雖然你有提到咧，阿田北俊議員提到對嗰個借貸成本就影響唔大，咁但係會唔會Basu Fee因應嗰啲即係資本要求等等咧，係令到銀行會？
即係借貸嘅時候，更需審慎噉樣樣。
噉就就算個成本冇增加，而會唔會令至到嗰個？
誒，借貸會困難咗噉樣樣。
噉就誒，我唔知道有冇辦法可以知道主席，即係雖然咧，即係我我又唔係話特登要求，誒叫啲人同我講下，咁但係就即係銀行你知道就。
咁呢個係國際協議，香港跟住做噉啊，做啦噉樣樣。咁但係銀行啊，照做噉樣樣。咁但係對中小企嗰個影響啊，或者對嗰啲誒即係銀行嘅使用者嚟講，有啲咩影響啊？噉樣樣有冇辦法可以行？有冇辦法可以評估到嚇？即係客觀啲評估到就。
誒咪。
I think that the price of credit and the availability of credit is actually affected by many factors. I mean, regulation would be one of them, but I mean, competitive pressures may also be sort of a heavy factor weighing in banks' decisions, and as would be relationship issues with with their customers. So.
There's a whole variety of issues that might come into the mix, and I think with something like Basel III, you have to balance against the cost factor that it actually does bring some benefits. So investors, for instance, will expect the banks to comply with Basel III, and to the extent the banks do so,
They may receive lower costs of funding, lower costs of capital, because they will be perceived to be safer. So the view of investors and the view of other regulators on banks is another factor that we need to we need to balance. So what we're trying to do, I think, with Basel III is a balanced framework that bolsters bank resilience while
whilst not inhibiting banks' sustainable lending, sustainable contribution to economic development.
我我 understand that passport-free may or might bring in some benefits to.
The banks, the investors. But my questions in particular relates to.
The user size which include.
no the SMEs in Hong Kong.
and also you know the general public or the potential borrowers.
我諗我嘅問題係具體嘅，我理解你可能帶入嚟啲好嘅優勢，但係你話邊個係負面嘅影響？邊個係影響？特別係對使用者、對消費者，或者係對，例如，有幾百家或者幾千家嘅中小企業，佢哋有冇？
要 borrow money from the bank.
As I mentioned, the banks are already holding this capital. They are already well capitalised, so there is no reason to assume that their behaviour will change markedly under Basel III. They are holding these buffers at the moment, so the cost of that is something that they are already bearing.
所以你 assume 或你 logic 是， There shouldn't be any impact.
Yes, yes, on the basis that the Basel III ratios are already, generally speaking, met by the banks in Hong Kong.
Actually, thanks for the question. So, actually, one of the main objective of Basel III is to increase the resilience of banks and the banking sector, and in such a way they will be able to absorb losses eventually. So, the objective is that bank will be able to continue.
ending to the real economy and the enterprises within which, including the SMEs, not only at good times and also at bad times. So in in such a way, actually, parcel three is beneficial to the general real economy, including the SMEs.
嗯。
政府就都講咗下，就係銀行界當然喺好早期都有一路，因為呢段時間都唔係話短㗎啦，起碼超過兩至三年嘅時間咧喺度做各間銀行都根據M A咧已經成立咗一個叫巴塞爾誒協議小組噉樣嘅。
去各個銀行自己啊，去研究點樣跟噉啊。我所知嘅背景就係話，大多數銀行喺銀行公會即係都幫手提醒咗之後咧，大家都即係都研究過，包括誒貸款會唔會增加咗困難啊？誒成本會唔會增加？咁呢呢啲咧就。
如果暫時以香港嗰個銀行業嘅呢個現有嘅誒，即係整個誒誒銀碼嘅規定咧，就個ratio咧就完全係可以達到嘅。咁所以咧短期內都睇唔到話一定會出現好大嘅增加咗呢個成本。
同埋會帶嚟咗好大嘅中小企借唔到錢呢個風險。咁當然而家成個風險就係話會係未來長期落去嘅啲國際性，如果都未必個個做得到嘅時候咧，咁有啲再爭相要誒加資本。
噉啊，即係而家香港都聽到嗰啲銀行都需要誒再發啲啲股，即係畀一啲投資者等佢哋再增加資本。咁呢個係未來，我諗個趨勢都會有嘅啊。噉我諗誒，睇下金管局特別係財經事務局，你哋對而家銀行嗰個現時嘅。
嘅所有嘅即係誒，所謂即係個資本資本充足嘅比率方面咧，你哋嘅嘅即係監管角度咧，係認為誒喺起碼呢個第一步實施嘅時候咧，誒香港係有冇特別邊啲銀行或者有冇咩銀行係需要增加資本？你哋嘅手上。
係咪都已經足夠？誒，認為係可以做得到咧？
主席，我諗誒可以有一個簡單嘅補充啦。我再請根本局嘅同事比較詳細解釋啦。咁正如主席你正話所提到啦嚇，香港現時銀行嗰個資本充足率係非常之充裕，亦都非常之強嘅喺亞洲嚟講。咁所以誒，正如主席提到，我哋睇唔到香港嘅銀行咧有一個大型因為巴蘇three而集。
知嘅需要，亦都睇唔到咧。佢哋因為Basel Three呢個個誒喺嚟緊啊一月一號嘅實施咧，係會有誒特別影響咗佢哋借貸嗰個嘅政策嘅喺度。而我哋誒同金管局喺制定呢一個Basel Three嘅條文嘅時候咧，亦都係咧經常同香港嘅銀行公會咧係保持非常。
之緊密嘅聯絡去制定有關嘅條文，佢哋都提過。噉我哋相信咧，呢一啲嘅條文咧，對於業界咧，亦都對於中小企嚟講嘅影響咧，係應該係唔高嘅。咁至於個別銀行嘅情況，我請金管局嘅同事再畀補充。
你哋可以補充下喺嗰個叫公共諮詢方面，誒有冇新嘅或者之前嘅一啲負面性質嘅反應咧？有冇解決到？有冇誒再需要一個公共諮詢嘅？有冇呢個噉嘅必要咧？你哋可以喺你哋嘅M A嘅角度。
去反映下你哋睇法。
We began consulting the banks in January, and I think we then we consulted again in June and again in August on the actual text of the rules. On each occasion, we received a variety of comments from the Hong Kong Association of Banks, and we have responded to all of those those.
We have accommodated several requests from the banks where they felt that we were being we were gold plating Basel III. We were we were moving beyond Basel III, and as I mentioned, we we we we moved back into alignment with Basel III at the request of those banks. There are one or two areas where, as I mentioned in my introductory remarks,
We we believe that we should.
stay with our existing approach, and I think you know that we we've covered all of the comments that the the banks raised.
有anything you'd like to?
係啊！電熱。
We are delighted to hear that the majority of our banks.
In good shape in the sense that.
even without the Basel III, they are probably up to the standard of what Basel III requires. But I think the chairman asked a question is that during your consultation period.
other than the Hong Kong Association of Banks, are there any individual banks that say that hey they will have to increase their capital in due course to meet this requirement, or are you saying with all the consultation that you have met, actually very few or actually no bank who have to increase their capital to meet this requirement?
Some banks may need to adjust their capital mix to meet the new requirements. Where we have the three new ratios, so you have a common equity tier one ratio. So some items that were previously counted as core capital will not fit within that common equity tier one ratio. So some banks will adjust their capital mix.
over time, but I think that we talk to all of the banks about their capital planning processes, and so we don't anticipate that that is going to cause a problem. They've seen this coming for several years, and they've positioned themselves to be able to do this.
誒唔該，誒主席。Thanks. So in addition to consultation that Carrens just mentioned, we also have been doing half yearly qualitative impact studies on a sample of banks that include large banks and also the small and medium sized banks in our sample for around two years. So
根據我們最新的評估，none of the bank will have any problem meeting the minimum capital requirements come 2013.
嗯，OK。
好噉就。
如果對呢部分冇咩特別嘅意見咧，我諗就要進入到。
誒嗰個立法嘅時間表個具體。
咁誒就按規定咧，只要審議期滿個deadline咧就係。
本月嘅廿一號啦，十一月廿一號。
就附屬法例作出預告，誒。
修訂嘅話，就係要十一月十四。
同埋誒，如果延要延展嗰個。
同意嗰個議案作出預告嘅話，就係。
誒十一月十六日。
咁所以我諗，我哋應該又唔會用好多時間嘅，就都可能由誒呢個政府方面嘅誒律師咧，應該可以對有關內容咧誒畀時間同大家都要誒高呼一下。
噉就。
銀龍工會方面，我問過佢哋話，未必需要有人派嚟，因為佢之前都有專專門睇咗。
咁所以，我依點就我諗都係由我哋委員會進行一次嘅審議咧，就即係應該可以足夠。咁如果要佢哋有需要嘅時候，佢先隨時再聯絡我哋誒，包括政府方面啊。
係啊，建議。即係對唔住，對呢個問題咧。
就我唔知其他委員點睇啦，即係你就問過下啲銀行業界，問佢哋有冇咩嘢上嚟呢個條例草案嘅委員會向我哋表達佢哋就話冇，但係可能調轉頭我啊，反而想見見佢哋啊，想問下佢哋啲嘢喎，即係呢度其實總之有一個議程，就係我哋需唔需要揾啲誒即係業界嘅銀行。
嚟傾傾，即係睇睇佢哋對呢方面嘅睇法。但係你就話你已經同佢傾過啦，佢哋唔想你個，佢哋冇嘢擔心嘅。
佢哋就因為頭先我講，佢哋老早就成立咗一個小組，即係每個銀行都有成立小組噉就係㗎啦，就做咗差唔多兩年嘅功夫。噉啊，就原則上都即係如果以而家嗰個叫做資本充足比率嘅要求咧，應該就已經完到大嘅問題。
噉啊，條文嘅方面咧太細節，佢哋都唔會話有啲咩需要去修訂啊等等。咁但係咧就可以即係實施咗，再一路睇。咁頭先都講，佢哋都會留意邊啲銀行，特別係外相信本地銀行絕對冇問題嘅。而家但係有冇外國銀銀行，因為佢嘅地區。
或者佢國家嗰個受影響咧，依樣嘢就等監管當局再隨時密切留意依方面嘅變化啦。但喺香港嘅限制咧，亦都比較強嘅，所以就啊工會本身咧就表達嘅就話，只要現時嘅要求嘅初步咧，就睇唔到有需要嘅。咁但係如果
因為議員需唔需要請佢嚟咧？噉我諗，我哋可以透過政府聯絡一下金本，因為金谷聯絡一下依個銀行公會派唔係代表嚟表達。但係，如果我出嚟銀行業嘅代表去，已經問過依個今次嘅依個叫做輪值主席。
匯豐銀行方面咧，啊，佢哋嘅表達咧，就暫時係冇呢個誒需要嚟就呢條提出。好，政府方面誒長啊。
廖生先講咗，跟住阿善源再問。誒，多謝主席。我諗我亦都可以補充咧。喺誒法例上咧，誒我哋誒定立咧誒二零一二年銀行業資本嘅修訂規則嘅時候咧，根據《銀行業條例》第九十七條咧，誒金融管理專員喺制定呢一個嘅附屬法例嘅時候咧。
係必須先諮詢咧財政司司長啦、銀行業務諮詢委員會、接受存款公司諮詢委員會啦、香港銀行公會同埋香港有限制牌照銀行及存款接受存款公司公會後，先至可以定立咧嚇眼前大家所見到嘅附屬法例嘅。噉我哋甚至咧係咧喺個。
過程裏面咧，同我哋有好多輪嘅會議，好多輪嘅書信來往，亦都係咧。甚至我哋將嗰個法例嗰個草擬本，即係我哋律政司嘅同事寫好咗之後，嗰個法例嗰個草擬本咧，直情係成份畀咗誒香港銀行公會啊，同埋有關嘅DTC associations咧去睇。噉佢哋都好仔細翻翻。
翻嚟咧，就話有邊啲條文，佢哋覺得唔清楚嘅，我哋改到佢哋大家滿意為止嘅。咁呢個過程咧係歷經歷咗成年嘅過程嚟嘅。咁正如即係主席所提到啦，銀行公會非常之係helpful嘅喺個process裡面，亦都畀咗好多咧誒好有用嘅意見，畀我哋金管局嘅同事，畀我哋政策局同埋。
誒律政司嘅同事參考，我哋都採納咗佢哋嘅意見嘅。咁所以喺個諮詢過程咧，我相信亦都已經足夠。多謝主席。
就誒，你哋有冇需要或者提供類似即係巖工喺最後即係基本同意嘅一啲文件，作為佢哋誒委員會，我哋誒嘅一個比較即係更更加勘拔到，我哋覺得諮詢係應該點足夠噉，可唔可以做？
少少呢啲嘅功夫，或者你哋去向誒牛工會直接誒問一個最後嘅佢哋對你哋進展到而家嗰個嘅consultation係咪已經足夠咧？咁之類係咪可以有啲咁back way提供咧？誒，我諗我哋可以邀請銀行工會畀一個誒，即係一個誒簡單嘅書面嘅。
回覆畀誒主席誒對呢個委員會，咁亦都可以即係誒表示佢哋係曾經係充分地係誒獲得諮詢嘅機會噉樣。O.K.我我覺得依個比較穩妥啲，係誒先馮仲佳，跟住先石禮。主席，我唔介意你咁做，不過似乎係咪應該我哋個委員會直接？
係啊！我哋自己個委員會即係，而家係我哋審議啊嘛。嗱，應該問我哋寫佢畀嗰幾個主要嘅機構問佢哋。佢哋冇意見，我哋唔使見佢啦。佢有意見，我哋咪先見咯。即係我又頭先我問你嘅時候，其實我都意思就係使唔使接觸其他人？咁但係即係既然阿James咁提到我哋，我個我支持我哋。
起碼我哋，因為而家係我哋審議，噉就應該我哋接觸誒，即係問佢哋，佢哋冇意見嘅，我哋又唔需要見佢，佢支持啦，可以生一月一號生效啦，ready啦。嗯。噉我睇完啲嘢，咪照做。好啊，好啊，呢個呢個建議，我諗我哋有少少修訂一下，由我哋秘書處代表我哋委員會咧，發出一個信畀茅工委臨時主席，等佢哋。咁咪有幾？
機構係咪？除咗銀行公會，仲有係誒存款係嘛？deposit呢啲先。係，我哋都對依幾機構都發出一個正式嘅誒諮詢佢哋。
問一問嘅意見。
係啊，石偉議員。主席啊，我誒好多謝啊啊田北俊議員頭先提出嚟嗰啲問題咧，呢個都係我哋嘅基本嘅責任，即係審核呢啲噉嘅政啊呢啲噉嘅條例㗎各方面咧。所以只所以政府開頭嗰張文件咧，就係唔夠詳細嘅，即係我哋唔係一個橡皮圖章喺度。
咧係即係咁去講，即係要一個議員去帶出呢個問題去問啦，而係你咁去講咧，就係有少少令到即係我哋做議員咧係有少少嘅懷疑，你係咪有冇做足嘅功夫咧？如果你係有做足，你應該係個成個due process，即係due process咁去嚇情。
最上要咁去做咧，我希望即係將來咧，主席即係係喺呢方面嗰個啲啲政府啲啲文件咧，唔該係清晰嘅去去寫。如果你要我哋盡快去誒批誒通過呢啲噉嘅條例好，各方面嘅文件好咧，你啲資料係要係要真係要捉去畀我哋去。
真正去做我哋嘅議員工作去做好，同埋咧審核任何嘅條例咧，我哋都好小心。所以頭先我都同意啦，阿阿善仲佳講咧，係應我哋係一個委員會個啊個嗰嗰個個組。多謝主席咁誒英明，係係去一早問咗，唔係唔信你主席，我哋係一百個percent。
佢哋但係都要做依個工作去做嚇，咁咧唔係政府，因為政府好多時政府壓逼嗰啲銀行咧，佢哋乜都say yes嘅主席。但係即係呢啲嘢就係咁啦。但係即係往以往我係叫佢嚟嗰陣時咧，都有啲人我係想聽下有啲反對聲音，唔係我係要支持反對啫，都聽到理解到嗰反對聲音係係點解要反。
反對咧，係佢哋個佢哋個理據係何在啊？係係邊度咧？咁即係我覺得，我哋應該係咁做嚇，都係粵語。係誒，政府有冇意見？誒，我冇特別嘅補充。我哋都喺我哋畀立法會嗰個資料嘅摘要裏面咧，詳細列出咗誒整個立法建議嗰個理據啦。
同埋我哋有誒公眾諮詢嗰個段落，亦都交代咗我哋個諮詢嘅過程嘅。當然，而議員對個別嘅資料係想誒，即係深入掌握嘅，我哋隨時係願意咧提供資料畀議員。多謝主席。好啊。
噉我哋都好盡責啊！即係我哋委員對於即係成個過程，因為呢啲涉及嘅亦都係公眾好大嘅利益。今後是否會影響到成個銀行界啊？呢個呢個香港金融中心啊，呢個運作裏邊，如果遵守某啲新嘅要求之後咧，會唔會造成一啲？
啲中小企啊，有啲誒有關借貸啊等等嘅變化咧，咁呢點我諗作為委員，我哋都係一個。
必須把關啊！政府將嗰個成個過程裏邊咧，如果我哋誒要了解嘅，我哋都有責任去瞭解清楚。
好嘅，噉就對呢個。
審議嘅具體時間表咧，我就想都徵詢下大家意見啦，就。
秘書處有兩個時間表係拎出嚟睇睇，等大家意見，就係十一月十三號星期二嘅上晝十點四十五分至十二點四十五分一個時段。
另外一個時段咧，就係。
十一月十六號星期五嘅上晝八點三十分至十點三十分，誒總共有兩個嘅時段係可以選擇，係嘛？
係選在呢兩個時段嘅。
三號係幾點啊？誒，十三號係十點四十五分早上至十二點四十五分。
誒星期五會好早啦，就八點三十分至到十點三十分。
係啊，呢位主席有冇查過撞咗乜嘢panel啊？冇事啊，我手上冇撞撞到少少嘅，我諗誒睇先，我見到就。
啊！啊，唔係喎，我個我褪咗啦。誒，一個大大立法會嗰啲團嗰啲可以，我我到時抽翻身出嚟得嘅。就另外一個就八點三十分嗰個，好似就緊接住先有幾個panel嘅啫。我都仲有三個panel。星期五主席係嘛？啊？星期五嗰個八點三十分。係啊，嗰八點三十分係應該係。
十點幾先至有幾個pin到跟住嘅，有幾個pin到我就撞咗後邊咧，就唔撞前面嘅。即係如果唔延唔延時間得嘅，係應該做得到嘅。睇下邊個時間大家都到，希望十六號早上嗰日得閒啲嘅。好，你寧願誒提早早啲開始嗰個，即係。
十六號早上八點半嗰個係咪？
係咪田少？係係啊！我唔中意八點半嘅，不過我星期二早上有啲嘢，十三號早上我就唔得。咁大家住十六號早上。有冇唔同意見咧？對依一個日子，因為啊田議員就prefer依個。會唔會睇其他點睇啊？啊，有冇其他嘅遇到困難咧？兩個。
覺得嘅話咧，噉我哋就揀後者，就十一月十六號嘅星期五早上八點三十分至到十點三十分呢個時段。
噉就係我哋下一次審議嘅具體時間。
呢個我哋全串套㗎啦嘛，三個都一齊㗎咯，係嘛？可以處理多少？
誒冇錯啦。嗱，如果如果我哋唔介意咧，今日可以做緊部分先嘅。如果大家時間都許許可嘅話，噉我哋請政府律師方面咧，可以帶帶住我哋咧就開始咗噉啊，今日嘅審議工作先。
噉啊，係政府。
誒政府提議咯，啊由政府提議呢三個附屬法例，邊個誒由邊個開始，同埋邊位負責，即係邊一個誒法例係今日審議。
同埋邊一位負責？請。
政府方面係邊位？
誒，主席係嚇誒。噉我諗咧誒，我哋可以先處理咗兩條係比較簡單嘅啊附屬法例嗰個啦。誒，就分別係誒L.N.嘅一五七，就係嗰個啊Multilateral Development Bank嘅Specification嗰個notice咧，嗰個就。
其實只係一板紙嘅啫，噉就誒係話喺我哋嗰個specifications，誒banking誒specification of multilateral development bank嗰個notice裏面咧，加咗啊呢個阿MIGA呢個銀行落去嘅，咁嗰個嘅審議就好簡單嘅啫，我相信秘書處都係。
畀咗誒文件啊，畀誒委員啦，就係誒我哋只係加咗誒多邊投資個擔保機構喺入邊嘅，咁相對比較簡單嘅呢一份。
即係加一間機構嘅。咁呢個就係呢個Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency咧，係World Bank旗下嘅一個嘅agency嚟嘅。噉我哋呢一個嘅啊加入呢一個嘅agency咧，就係純粹係配合咧即係Basel Committee裡面最新嘅決定嚟嘅。咁所以呢個相當係係一個技術。
性嘅修訂就冇特別嘅政策嘅改動嘅。
咁如果，
委員係冇特別嘅意見咧，噉我諗亦都可以請委員咧，同時係審核埋我哋嗰個commencement notice啊。
個commencement notice就係誒banking amendment ordinance誒二零一二commencement notice二零一二嗰個生效嗰個日期嗰個公告嘅。咁個生效日期就係由財經事務及副務局誒局長咧係制定呢一個公告啦。噉啊，只在咧係定立喺誒二零一三年。
一月一號咧，作為咧係啊Banking Ordinance Amendment二零一二，即係銀行修訂條例二零一二咧，嗰個生效日期，咁亦都係一個生效日期嘅公告，咁相對係比較簡單，噉我相信喺草擬上亦都冇特別嘅誒情況。
咁誒呢兩條簡單嘅處理咗之後咧，咁誒不。
係誒市議員中文版嗰度咧係。
我哋係咪冇譯出嚟咁解嘅？喺個中文嗰個譯稿度，之零零一個版啊，零零一嗰個版嗰度咧，喺左邊咧有個。
即係好怪嘅，即係A、B跟住咧就冇中文嘅，佢C就有亞洲發展銀行，跟住D至M咧就有冇冇中文嘅，跟住我哋加咗個N咧就有中文嘅。
噉係係個草嘢點講？英文好簡單，出方圍我明曬啦，係嘛？
定係中文係冇引出嚟咁解嘅啫。
今晚喺。
冇喎。
佢本身冇中文，係咯？係咪即係本身係冇中文嘅，或者？
政府方面。
我見到A、B咧就係譬如International Bank of Reconstruction and Development，The International Finance Corporations，C咧就阿赤發這樣啦，噉啊冇誒就有中文喺度啦，咁即係呢度本來應該呢一個呢一個A至M咧都係。
英中文嚟嘅，但係佢中文都好啊，佢都係冇中文，所以等咗英文落去，係咪噉嘅意思啊？
啊，我。
誒中文。
哦，有中文名嘅佢就直接就攞個中文名，但係如果冇中文名，佢就唔同嘅譯成中文。係，咁所以咧，你誒講係啱嘅。佢因為係冇中文嘅譯名咧，就全部就照照抄翻佢英文嘅內容。
所以入邊嘅中文版咧，只出現到嘅就係你剛才講嘅嗰兩個機構嘅啫。
係咪政府方面？你哋主席誒，我我哋嘅理解都係一樣嘅嚇。O K，即係喺個咁即係而家嗰個新加嗰個多邊投資擔保機構，就個International Finance Facility for Immunisation嗰個都係佢嘅正式中文譯名嚟㗎咯喎。誒唔係嗰個誒Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency就係個。
英文嘅版本啦，係咁喺嗰個中文嘅法例度咧，我哋會加入多邊投資擔保嘅，噉就係個中文譯名個multilateral係啦，OK係啦嚇咁OK收到明白OK。即係而家其實呢一部分裏邊咧，即係將來改咗之後咧，得C同N咧就係走中文嘅咗，其他嗰啲A、B、D至M係。
都仍然係冇咗文。如果有中文名嗰啲，我哋就已經填咗落去；否則，誒就誒佢哋現有嗰個法例嘅草擬就係用英文名去填落去。
誒，我都提醒睇下係唔係你再查清楚啊？因為如果照國際性嘅要求咧，有有可能嘅有好多都有譯有譯名唔整嘅，咁呢個係唔係已經查清曬？
誒的確係冇，噉我就我我都唔敢肯定。或者我請誒草二科嘅同事畀少少補充，係。
高爾科嘅同事有冇嘅補充？主席，我哋其實每次誒加呢啲誒機構名落去嘅時候咧，都係應該係金融管理局提供畀我哋，我哋都會問過佢有冇中文名嘅。如果冇中文名嘅話，就會寫翻英文落去咯。
即係最終都係金融管理局嘅資料，啊有就有，冇就唔會再。你哋都唔會。我哋唔會幫佢譯個中文名，因為即係官方嘅名。即係如果個機構佢冇官方嘅中文名，我哋就唔會夾硬係為咗法律草擬香港法律草擬嘅需要。
就幫佢作一個中文名噉。咁但係金管局本身嘅就search方面，即係個調查方面係查足曬㗎啦，就係得噉嘅名。噉我哋只能夠噉樣照。噉佢哋借呢個機會去睇睇啦，因為可咁多年前啲例咪成日都改。既然你鬥開呢條咧，你再檢查下有。
A至M咧，裏邊有冇啲已經以前冇英文嘅冇中文譯名，而家又執埋佢啦。我唔知你係咪合適，不過咧就我見到就係本來係中文嚟嘅，都係得兩個中文，都係得都係得英文咁解嘅。係好都都即係比較比較少啊，得咁少嘅又有中文喎，但係得噉。
少咁呢個係值得我哋有個問話符號㗎嚇，就希望M A方面咧再做多一次功夫添啊！喺下次如果方便嘅話，就再提供翻畀委員會。
好，跟住政府方面係。
第啊第三條係咪今日可以？啊第三條就係嗰個BankingCapitalAmendmentRules二零一二啦。主席，正如我相信大家手頭上嘅資料，亦都係誒呢一個嘅誒嘅規則咧，係非常之係龐大嘅一套規則啦。噉我所以想啊，即係誒。
議員啊，或者主席誒，你可唔可以誒，即係誒指示一下，究竟誒，你會想我哋點樣同委員係誒逐步逐步傾落去啊？定一話係誒由誒法律誒顧問或者誒會唔會有特別嘅係草擬上有特別嘅誒提問對我哋，又或者誒？
會唔會係誒？如果議員對個別嘅條款有意見，我哋再誒喺誒透過書面嘅形式誒向委員會補充。因為誒，如果我哋逐條逐條噉樣掃落去嘅話，就可能嗰個需要嘅時間亦都係會比較多。咁所以我想即係主席，你指示一下究竟誒想誒。
行政當局點樣同議員逐條去審議有關嘅條文？誒，通常呢啲辦委員會都係即係跟政府盡量用你哋草擬嘅角度去介紹嘅啫。因為如果有問題，我哋當然會提出嚟啦。咁但係咧，就由於相當多係條文嘅技術性，咁如果係原則。
性嘅政策方面嘅咧，我哋都可能會隨時會提出問題。咁所以可以誒速度方面由你哋可以控制嘅，即係起草資源方面。如果你哋係好多係一般性嘅，噉我諗你哋就誒可以帶人快一啲，效率可以高啲。係啊，田議員。
我同意嘅，即係一方面啊，可以誒政府嗰邊咧，好似話齋咁大揼，係咪真係全部去咧？咁喐佢哋認為唔需要嘅，係咪佢哋揀重要嗰啲雜要解釋咁？當然我都要睇睇我哋嘅法律顧問嗰邊啊，有冇代我哋睇到啲咩嘢誒可以提出嚟啦？咁咧事實上係可以慳啲時間，就唔使。
喺每張紙每頁去講，而嗰啲可能根本啊，亦都唔係咁關鍵性嘅問題啦。係，我哋都係用咗噉嘅方法啫。好嘛，由你哋就帶一啲主要嘅要點，噉我哋法律顧問咧可以隨時補充提提供翻畀誒委員留意嘅。啊。
冇問題嘅，主席。噉我諗我可以先開始誒，做一個簡單嘅介紹啦。噉我嘅介紹都係以我哋嘅立法會嗰個嘅誒資料嘅摘要咧，作為一個藍本。噉我帶到去個別嘅條文嘅時候，如果議員有提出，可以隨時係誒可以誒係發問，噉我哋再畀補充。
噉啊，銀行業嗰個資本嗰個修訂規則咧啊，最重要咧，我哋嘅要求就係話要修訂最低個資本比率嘅規定，同埋監管資本嘅定義啦。咁喺呢度咧，我哋就係新定咗第一A部嘅，特別係新定咗第三A同埋三B條嘅嚇定名咧，係二零一三。
今年起咧，適用於認可機構嘅三項啊，最新嘅最低資本充足比率嘅。咁所以你會見到第三A同埋三B條咧，就係列咗係啊。
列咗由二零一三年啦、一四年啦同埋一五年開始咧，銀行嗰個最低資本充足比率。誒，畀發言顧問先同你講講。
誒。
哦，好啊。係，我提議咧，其實誒政府會考慮咧跟翻個誒誒零零零一噉樣樣，跟住條條咁容易跟啲啊，因為噉樣樣會好要飛嚟飛去，好難跟。O K O K，因為呢份我哋就啱啱先收到嘅，其實其實係跟翻誒，我哋呢份咧係標明文本係跟翻咧誒條。
誒L.N.一五六嗰個嗰度噉樣計，噉樣標明出嚟㗎，咁所以跟嗰個格網就會用。
We want to start.
所以。
新資本 adequacy ratios， that Jackie's just referred to about this， actually set out in Part 1A of the， which is entitled capital adequacy ratio， and。
所以，MarkUp copy，它喺Part Three。Part Three。
zero zero four three。
page number zero zero zero one。
and and explain to us the mark up the changes.
佢哋有係咪啊？佢哋。
嗯。
啊，sorry，yeah。
即係跟你嘅page，即係我大家睇到嘅page number噉啊！你一路講第幾頁有邊啲需要你提畀我哋嘅，噉你講page先。
嗯。
嘅版本，咁所以我哋而家誒，我哋而家可以開始請金管局嘅同事再誒，即係作版做一個簡單嘅介紹啦。咁如果係誒，委員有個別嘅條文有特別嘅意見，咁可以隨時提出。咁誒，或者法律顧問有特別嘅指示，亦都可以隨時提出，好嘛？噉我請金管局嘅同事。
畀個簡介。
所以啊。
Right from the first page, that means zero zero zero one to.
page誒。
是，sorry。
to zero zero to page thirty five, I actually set out the
啊，嗰。
sorry，need a bit of time to get used to this version。
哦，forty-three，哦，yes，嗯。
啊！
到頁43，是實際設出那些新定義，需要理解，以瞭解如何解讀銀行資本規則。所以，有些這些新定義被納入，以應付部分的規範。
And some of the definitions are incorporated as consequential changes to the amendments to the existing banking capital rules.
again to reflect the Basel Three requirements.
and.
So then, those definitions will be followed by.
The new capital adequacy ratios, which is the key part of Basel III, that has been referred to earlier by Jackie.
所以誒。
Members can refer to, in particular, to section three that is on page forty-five. That defines the capital adequacy ratio as the three ratios that we have been talking about: the CET one capital ratio, the T one capital ratio and the total capital ratios. And these are the
Three minimum requirements contained in the Basel III framework.
So and what follows are the the level of the ratios that authorised institutions have to comply with in the transitional period that we have been discussing about. So 3A is the transitional the rate the level ratio.
That applies in the first two years of implementation, and 3B is the ratio that will apply from 2015 onwards. As members will know from the electrical brief, the transition period will run from 2013 to 2019.
所以這些 ratios and levels actually reflect the transitional time frame of the bansal free capital sends.
and that then we come to
啊，page forty-five。
啊！得。
啊！
Specifies the basis on which authorised institutions have to calculate their capital ratios, because banks may have subsidiaries. So, we, as our usual practice, we will require banks to comply with the ratios, both on.
Solo basis, that means the bank alone basis and also the consolidated basis. So that merely reflect those requirements.
嗯。
所以， we come to.
唔好講。
佢嗰個。
嗱，雖然比較technical啦，我唔知其他同事有冇興趣，但係就係即係你page三廿二嗰啲新增。
新增嘅定義咧。
即係如果恕饒恕我啦，我啱啱誒即係我上屆我唔知我啲同事有冇解釋過啦。但係呢個咩additional tier one啊，誒add one誒additional tier one capital instrument啊，跟住有嗰啲誒CETI啊CETI一嘅capital instrument，同埋即係CETI capital ratio，你解下好喎都要。
因為我哋阿蘇，我哋全部識曬嘅。
嗯。
哦，OK，即係嗰度全部都係新嘅定義嚟㗎嘛，唔係舊嗰啲嚟㗎嘛，係嘛？Yeah，Yeah。
So thanks for the question. So and so this part set out the definition of those new terms. Actually, under Basel Three, capital the regulatory capital of banks are divided into few tiers. The most
The best quality is what we call the common equity, common equity capital, and that is basically those ordinary shares issued by banks and the retained earnings reserve that sort of thing. And then the second tier is the additional tier one that members just referred to. So and.
And the third tier is what we call the tier two capital. So, one of the key focus of the Basel III is to tighten the definition of different tiers of capital, so that the quality of capital
是實際higher，所以for each tier of capital，we will later specify some criteria that bank must meet in order to for the tier of capital for the capital instruments to be qualify as as that tier。所以we will have detailed criteria.
Later on, when we come to the the sub-singular part of the rules to define, actually define that in quite the detail.
有誒。
我。
T.I.
One, C E T One and Tier One。
啊，所以誒誒T1係總合嘅誒CET1 plus additional T1。
因為the Basel Committee set the minimum three minimum ratios. The first one is the CET one ratio, and the second one is the Tier one ratio, and the third one is the total capital adequacy ratio. So they do not set up sub ratio requirement at the level of.
Regional Tier One，所以Tier One capital is necessary。
This one, yeah.
所以，其實T一 ratio係CET一capital plus additional T一capital。
Tier One Capital Ratio includes CET One Capital Ratio plus additional CET One.
Yup.
A T one, T one, A T one.嗯，嗯
個考試温度。
似。
所以，In Free and Free A and Free B，你係實際係一個轉型增加。
In the C E T one ratio and tier one ratio and also total capital ratios. Yeah, correct.
Okay. Yup. Correct.
所以，如果你 map
This requirement on the first day of.
on the first day of
two, o, one, three.
So what is the situation of our banks in Hong Kong? They will have no problem. Yeah, based on our
半年期量投資者亦都沒有問題，達成那些最低要求。所以，他們都超過這些要求。所以，如何達到二、三、四？
二二一四，係
So up to up to 2015.
所以，The banks in Hong Kong are already above 3A and 3B also. So they are above, for example, CETI, CET1 capital ratios less than.
four point four point five per cents， so they are.
They must be about four point five, right?
And for tier one capital ratio, they must be about six, and total capital ratio about eight. Correct.
所以。
You said according to your reportings, all the banks in Hong Kong have already met the requirement up to 2015. Yeah, yeah, that's our assessment. Yeah, that's right. So we we are well capitalised.
yes。
哦。
可以繼續。
Okay.
所以Three C， as we've already mentioned， is to specify the basis。
Which bank calculate its capital adequacy ratio? So normally, for a bank that has subsidiaries, we usually require the bank to calculate those ratios both on a consolidated basis and a solo basis. So that is to enable the MA to specify the basis of calculation. That actually.
reflect the existing requirement. That part is actually from the existing banking ordinance.
So coming to page 46 is just some extra definition to.
啊。
to to make clear about the interpretation of different terms that used before in sections three.
誒拍雲A。
啲。
所以。
哦，即係。
Okay，then we come to page 53。So another。
Elements that we seek to introduce under Basel III is the introduction of an internal model method for the calculation of counterparty credit risk, and Section 10A.
是實際上要make available，and members can can see here here and there the reference to the term IMMCCR。That is actually what we are just referring to the internal model method for calculation of the counterpart credit risk approach。
所以。
So，誒誒，does，do，members，have，any，queries，on，誒？
The IMMCCR.
and that will actually take.
take us to。
section。
嗯。
是先生。
傾。
10C， yes， is actually page 59， in。
57，sorry。
58， is also on CCR。
Yes, so the introduction of the IMMCCR framework and those related provisions is going to take us to page 58 of the draft that we have on hand.
嗯。
next。
sixty three。
yeah。
So another another new elements that we seek to introduce under the CCR framework is the calculation of credit risk for exposure to CCP. CCP stands for central counterparties, and it's actually reflects global.
改革 on the OTC derivative markets. That
banks exposure to CCPs because of the
That will help banks manage their exposure to CCP and to reduce the risk of their counterparty credit risk exposures. The Basel III framework allows banks exposures to CCP that are that are defined as a that that that are qualified as a
that are qualified, meeting certain requirements, they will allocate lower risk weight to banks' exposure to such CCPs. So
For those CCPs that do not qualify based on the specified criteria that we also include in the rules, they will be subject to a higher risk weight. That part is actually reflect those requirements. And there's also part of the enhanced CCL for.
我們將會試圖透過修訂規則來引入。
所以，next bit is。
八八三。
所以第83反映 consequential revisions to the definition of capital.
Because Basel III, in addition to specifying the three new minimum ratios that we've just talked about, they also also tighten the definition of
capital. So that part actually set out. If a bank want to include certain instrument, as for example, common equity tier one capital, additional tier one capital, or tier one capital or tier two capital, they need to satisfy those criterion. Specify under.
呢part。
嗯。
So again, that part begins with the relevant terms defined, and as member can see from page 83 through to 80.
eighty six, I guess eighty six, yeah, yeah, and then members can see on the bottom right hand corner and the the link two is um.
The definition of T1 capital that a member has.
問過，問
And then.
And then we go on to what is the characteristics of different tier of capital, and here we will set out individually what sort of criterias a bank an instrument should meet in order to be qualified as under each tier of capital. For instance, and
Section 38， that is on page 87。 Those provisions have to be satisfied in order for an instrument to be qualified as CET1 capital。 And then on 80 page 88 that that
會被followed by additional tier one capital.
什麼的criteria need to be satisfied?
and then。
唔該。
誒就係喺我哋制定咧呢一個嘅banking capital amendment rules嘅時候咧，我哋有參考到咧係巴蘇committee咧發出嗰個嘅政策文件嘅。咁所以喺法例嘅草擬上咧，我哋嗰個改動嘅空間其實唔高嘅，因為誒巴賽爾嗰個委員會咧係就所有有關呢啲嘅條款，即係譬如話。
Tier One Capital啊，Tier Two Capital啊，嗰啲嘅regulatory deductions咧，係全部發出咗非常之充足嘅個技術性嘅文件咧，係講清楚究竟邊一啲嘢可以扣減，邊一啲嘢係列作什麼capital嘅。咁所以喺字眼用詞上咧，我哋喺嗰個法律草擬上咧，係一定要跟足咧嗰個巴塞。
巴賽爾嗰個委員會咧發出嘅文件，以便咧就係話全球採用巴賽爾協定三嘅其他嘅comparable jurisdiction咧，都係用噉樣嘅處理嘅。咁所以喺嗰個法律草案嘅上面咧，根本嗰個同事都同啊，即係佢哋一方面喺巴賽爾委員會有啊開會啦，另一方面咧就亦都有係。
畀呢啲嘅文件咧，係畀誒我哋誒律政司草擬嘅專員啦，係處理。咁所以咧就唔存在咧係誒個別嘅provisions係話啊，我哋特別係係嗰個喺嗰個草擬嘅形式上咧，就唔係話我哋自己作出嚟，即係我哋香港唔係話逐條逐條噉樣作出嚟，好多都。
係咧，係直接係採納咧，係巴塞爾嗰個委員會頒發嘅頒布嗰個政策文件。噉我哋就要跟足噉樣，以便全世界都採用嘅。咁所以我可以繼續咧，請同事係誒同大家介紹個別嘅條文。但係我想派個定心丸畀大家，就係呢啲就唔係話我哋自己刪。
埋門即係自己作出嚟嘅一啲嘅誒條文嚟嘅，讓我哋有即係足夠嗰個係國際嗰個參考，亦都方便咧。我哋嘅銀行啦嚇，同埋佢哋喺其他地方嘅branches咧，都大家採用同一套準則嘅時候咧，都係一set嘅準則係世界通用噉樣嘅。多謝主席。
啊！啲。
啊，是，即係草法律草擬嗰邊嘅同事，噉佢哋有冇比較過，即係我哋嘅drafting同嗰啲，即係Basel Free Committees佢哋嗰啲drafting有冇咩即係major discrepancies？嗯。
係。
誒。
係咪先？先答先。
而其實我哋喺收到誒呢套誒巴隨協議三嗰度文本嘅時候咧，其實係經過金融管理局嗰邊去係篩選過，佢哋邊啲係一定要跟，邊啲係可以有少少modification噉樣。然之後其實我哋基本上因為呢啲係咁技術性嘅收嘅嘅文件咧。
基本上，我哋喺法律草擬嗰個角度嚟講咧，只能夠係幫佢睇下同現有我哋自己嘅法例咧，有冇誒衝突嘅地方，或者有冇啲係唔清楚嘅地方，或者本身嘅銀行業條例本身已經有一啲嘅定咗嘅定義詞啊，或者有一啲條文咧係要用翻我哋原本嘅草擬方式去寫噉樣。
但係其實內容嗰方面咧，其實我哋就冇乜點可以去誒，即係去斟酌嘅。我哋要follow啦，即係噉，我要問金融管理局，可唔可以喺你介紹畀我哋嘅時候咧，你要特別突出咧，就係。
頭先因為阿Michael、阿林生所提就話經金融管理局篩選噉樣樣，咁當然咧，即係可能你哋要localize，即係要本地化啲嘢。咁可唔可以喺你介紹嘅時候突出就係話有咩嘢我哋同Basufi有嗰個？
譬如話，你而家喺度三三第三十八段，即係page八十七，我照跟㗎啦，冇喐過噉，噉我哋可能都。
都即係我哋跟，既然我哋跟，咁跟足啦噉嘅樣。咁如果你去到某個位，你話畀我哋聽，嗱邊度咧係同Bustle Free我哋有啲乜嘢咧？有啲乜嘢嘅唔同？
噉我哋就睇唔同嗰啲噉嘅樣。
我哋可以繼續用噉嘅形式，好嘛？好啊。即係你強調嘅就係有改動或者有差異嘅嗰啲就為主。噉你剛才啲補充咗世界上大量都係跟巴蘇菲嘅嗰個文字咧，嗰啲嘢就可以誒減省啲。
係誒，sorry，誒啊，田議員，你都係同樣嘅問題。等我搞清楚先，第一件事係咪我哋話我哋攞住呢部嘢啊？
即係我哋呢個banking capital rules係唔係同其他而家要遵守Basel Three嗰扎國際嘅大國？
基本上係大同小異嘅，幾乎係差唔多噉嘅嘢啦。但係如果問我一間國際銀行，冇可能去到倫敦啊！
就倫敦嚟畀份噉嘅嘢我，巴黎畀份噉嘅嘢我，呢度都香港畀份噉嘅嘢我，噉我盤數唔使搞㗎啦。即係我有感覺，你呢份嘢本身啊，你基本上全部係差唔多嘅嘢嚟㗎。所以咧，係差唔多嘅情況之下咧，就可以全部啊作某啲修訂。如果銀行喺香港個分攤又好，誰？
市嘅分堂輪到個分堂咧。
大節上都係遵守曬噉，即係話其實我哋香港自己冇乜走盞嘅，因為呢啲噉嘅T啊，即係啊，善於運嗰啲One啊、Two啊嗰啲T啊Capital咧嘅全世界一用咧就個個國家都通用，所以嗰啲國際銀行咧全部要全部一個版本得㗎啦，唔使嚟到香港咧適應你香港嘅版本，去到歐洲係邊個版本？
係咪先？如果係咁咧，即係可能我哋從處理呢方面啊，作為一個本地嘅立法會議員啊，噉啊，放心程度應該高啲。一嚟咧，我哋好多都冇冇得話我哋話事嘅，而咧國際上睇過曬咧，度度行得通咧，我哋遵守曬一齊行同一個法例，係咪即係噉嘅意思啊？
你哋咪confirm係基本上係。
一致，差唔多叫一致。
可能。
Sorry, you mean you go back to English? Maybe the simple question. I'm a little behind you. Yeah, I know the translation. Basically, different jurisdictions. The Basel Committee writes Basel III in a certain way, and then different jurisdictions bring it into force in their own jurisdictions.
In whichever way suits their legal system, so we put it into place by subsidiary legislation. Others may use guidelines, and in putting it into force in subsidiary legislation, we do use different wording to the extent that it is in legislative format, so that it is different. So we don't track every single word that's in the bar.
Basel III document into the legislation, but in terms of say common equity tier one, additional tier one, those kind of things, we do follow the the Basel Committee's listings. So really, we're just looking to make changes if there's a there's a better legislative way of saying it. We're not trying to change.
The substance, but some of the language that perhaps the Basel Committee uses, the bank does nothing. We need to say the authorised institution. So, if you expect to see an exact lift, that is not what you would see. But the content. So, they have criteria for CET1 and they've got 14 of them. We should have all 14.
in in our criteria.
即係我諗應該可以接受，就係因為嗰個計算嘅具體咧就有一個一致嘅誒，威數又係規定咗嘅。咁只不過係每度嘅文字上邊嗰啲法律用語嘅習慣咧，可能有啲差異咧。咁但係，不論有咩。
差異都好，我哋嘅委員都好想知道，如果有啲差異係你哋係點解同人家有差異咧？依啲係重更加重要啲，要一致嘅就係人哋間人哋間倫敦嘅銀行嚟到呢度嘅分行，佢又係咁做；調轉嚟我哋嘅分行開喺倫敦咧，又係要咁做嘅，噉就。
噉樣問題就唔大嘅。
噉樣嘅approach去誒大議員去睇落去嘅，噉我哋而家係八十七頁開始。We are now on page eighty-seven, and then we continue to invite members to examine individual provisions.
So and so and maybe I just supplement that in terms of as far as the substance or content is concerned, the the banking capital rules that that we are looking at actually already reflect what is in Basel Three. There are on a few areas that we seek to go a little bit beyond.
單雙月，因為本地的狀況，可能當我們到那時，我會強調給成員的注意。所以，對於餘下的，我們只是，正如我們剛剛提到，這只是語言問題，我們用來反映單雙月政策的本意。所以，87。
嗯。
87, that's section 38, actually sets out what has to be, what criteria to be satisfied in order for an instrument to be qualified as CET1 capital. And here the lists are fully in line with Basel III requirements.
and then section 39 that is on page 88 the additional tier one capital.
criteria。
and then。
跟誒。
The third tier, the tier two capital, that is on page ninety.
yes，likewise，it set out the criteria to be satisfied in order for the instrument to be qualified as a tier two capital. and up here，I just want to refer also the members to a few schedules.
That's a few schedule. That is schedule four A, four B and four C's, and that is in because they are interrelated, and so I think that that will facilitate our explanation and members' understanding of the criteria. And maybe we just have a look at.
page， is it forty?
Yeah，four hundred and eighty-four. Thanks， Jackie.
嗯，Yeah，and.
So these set out the qualifying criteria to be met to in order for the instrument to be qualified as CET1, Schedule 4A, and then followed by Schedule 4C that is on page.
嗯。
That is on page.
486， that is schedule 4B， another newly added schedule to specify what conditions to be satisfied in order for an instrument to be qualified as additional Tier 1 capital.
And then schedule for C.
That is on page.
That starts from take four hundred ninety four. Four hundred ninety four, yeah. That sets up the criteria to be satisfied in order for instrument to be qualified as tier two capital.
嗯，我。
So we go back to the main main sections and.
啊，所以我們 just。
talk about the tier two capital that will.
Take us to，我，我，just ask that，other than the than the cross， basically is on the Basel Committee。
我認為，我們的銀行資本規則和我們的銀行資本修訂通過了時間表。
或 sort of derive from.
The financial institutions based on the UK model.
所以係唔係？所以唔係。所以唔係
equivalent authority. So are we moving this over to mirror mirror whatever they're practising out of the London as international financial institution on this, or actually we come up with our own ideas on on the schedules four and four A.
Those provisions in the schedules mirror what is in Basel III. So the Basel Committee comes up with what it considers to be the criteria for the different tiers of capital to ensure that it's genuinely loss-absorbing. And then in London, when they implement the European Union's directive CRD IV, they will carry
The same substantive listing, although albeit it might be in slightly different language. What one point that probably is worth making is I mentioned in my introduction that the Basel Committee are carrying out assessments, so they will come here. They they they've gone to.
the EU, they've gone to the US.
And they will do a line by line, and they will issue a report. So that if in any sense you are not compliant, you will get a not compliant, materially not compliant rating. Kerry, then correct me if I'm wrong. So I'm wrong to assume that our whole
Legislation that this came from the UK in the eighty s, ninety s. That's wrong. We came up with our own thing under HAMA. Yeah, based upon the Basel. Yeah, so so Basel. Sorry, not the Basel, the original one, the whole thing that we're looking at. The original one that you're looking at that's crossed out is Basel two, and that came from the Basel committee, and that replaced what was.
A Schedule Three in the Banking Ordinance, which was Basel I, which came out of the Basel Committee, I think, in about 1988. So basically, since about 1988, the capital rules in Hong Kong have more or less faithfully tracked Basel I, then Basel II. Sorry, Mr. Chairman, it does mirror the situation in London.
As the financial capital of the world in those days in the 80s. Yeah, they adopted Basel One and Basel Two, and they will adopt Basel Three once the the European directive comes into force. Usually, I think Europe uses via directive, and then the individual individual jurisdictions put it into their own rule books.
CRD IV I think is a mix of a directive and regulation which will take automatic effect in the jurisdictions. But yes, that they take the European version and put it into their own rulebook. Understand. So that's why all the international banks will have no trouble meeting the requirement of London, or Geneva, or Hong Kong. In essence, the more jurisdictions.
impose this, that almost the better for the international banks because as you point out, they can calculate in their subsidiaries up to the home on the same basis. So it is actually easier for them if all jurisdictions are in line, and more expensive and difficult if we're not. Okay, thank you. So you will point us to us items that are not sort of practice.
In those countries, but that's very rare. I think we probably there's just one or two items that we we will draw to your attention.
Right, and this will take us to the end of the different tier of capital that is on page 95. So maybe I just pause here for for a moment to see if members have any particular questions to raise in relation to the different tiers of capital. And then, if not, we'll move on to regulation.
税抵扣，那也必須考慮在釐定累積資本額時。
We won't have many questions or views because we cannot have a view, right? The tier one, two, three, it's ordered by the vessel committee. It's been practised in London, New York. So we just have to go along with it, right?
我哋just okay go，yeah okay，我哋just continue。
So it's from page ninety-five. So there are a number of items that the Basel framework require banks to deduct from their capital base. That is actually broadly divided into two types of items. The first type is the those intangible.
like goodwill and other intangible assets and items like deferred tax deferred tax assets etc. so these kind of instruments that are not regarded as being able to absorb losses in in the bank are so.
應該會被 deductible from the capital base， and the second type of items are what we what we call that will have a tendency to increase inflate the capital base in the financial sector. What we we term it double gearing items. That is banks.
投資額
嗯。
and perhaps there.
咦，好，唔使阿伯。
Yeah. Okay. I think here we should draw members' attention to the fact that we have some slight differences in the deductions to to to the Basel Basel III. The first is in relation to unrealised gains on property revaluation. Basel III will allow unrealised gains on property revaluation.
要被包括在共同股權Tier One，無限。
Without limit, because of the the historic volatility of property in Hong Kong, we are concerned that to allow it to be included in common equity tier one without limit would cause the capital base of the banks to be very volatile, which in turn underpins their lending. So if the if the if the base is too volatile, the lending may be
被pull back in times of if property prices fall, so we prefer to continue with the existing situation, which is that unrealised revaluation gains on property get recognised only in tier two, and even there they're subject to a 55 hair cut. So you can only recognise 45, and it's only within.
Tier Two，所以那那係一個差異從從巴爾茲爾三，The banks are fully aware of this and we have discussed it with them，但係它係現有的計算方法。
The other areas where we're slightly more stringent is that Basel III allows limited recognition of deferred tax assets for timing differences, and it allows limited capitalisation of mortgage servicing rights where you have sold a portfolio of mortgages but you receive fees for servicing them. That is not common.
在香港，我們沒有過去經驗可以衡量，這是否是實際上一個堅實的資本來源，可以納入CEt1。我們不認可延税資產或抵押服務權，所以我們比較嚴格。銀行們熟悉這個，因為這些是已經存在的減免。
唔，有少少唔realize。
Gain is the same as a realised loss, but if that's the practice.
I can't believe the Spanish banks could survive if they take into the unrealised loss of the property prices the way they are now.
要。
但你都 have 此 without limit。
Well, that's that you can recognise the the gain. This is new under Basel Three, so it hasn't come in yet. Gain equals to loss. You cannot just have before the gain and not the loss. Yeah, the losses should be recognised, but under Basel Three, going forward, you will be able to include the gain. We have a sort of asymmetrical treatment under I think Basel Two, correct? Where you.
Take the loss and don't recognise the gain. But under Basel III, you will be able to recognise the gain. That's the important thing. So that's that's the difference, which is what causes us the concern because it is an unrealised paper gain.
One other item I should just mention is that we have included our own anti-avoidance provision, because you are required to deduct within certain limits capital investments in other companies. We have put in an anti-avoidance provision so that if you
make a loan to a connected company, so it is characterised as a loan, but it is in fact a capital investment that can be deducted. So it's just to deal with recharacterisation risk.
嗯。
Mr. Chairman。
誒，呃，May may I suggest? I think，誒，In view of。
I think since you just voice out your
yeah not you know you just clarify the
差別，之間，呃，Localization和The Basel Three。
May I request, if you may, submit a paper to us, you know, detailing you know the substantial differences that how we deviate from Brussels III. That will actually satisfy you know, at least you let this committee know, and that will actually save our time to scrutinise the legislations. I think we we focus very much.
on the deviations, I don't think you said.
巴斯福委員會會來到我們的合規。
可唔可以提供嘅文件？可以㗎，OK，Yeah。
嗯，投保文件即係啊，就啊善語言嗰個要求，噉我就列出一個表，就係有邊啲地方我哋同巴塞爾協定嘅係有modification based on local circumstances嗰啲，噉我哋可以有一個文件，亦都可以註明埋個有關嘅條文喺邊一度，咁可以就可以節省咗。
議員寶貴嘅時間，我哋就係係啦，就係睇嗰嗰嗰啲條文，針對嗰部分去，係啦，針對嗰部分去解釋，亦都我哋可以喺下次嘅會議提供一個文件，噉就誒方便議員喺下次嘅會議去。
好，噉我諗就OK，好啦。噉啊，我哋等下一次，你一次過。冇問題，冇問題，好，多謝主席，唔該曬，好。
噉啊，今日到此為止，下次十六號見。Okay, we can do that. That makes more sense. That makes more sense.好，十六號先見。Okay, we understand.應該就問題唔大嘅。Understand.
O.K.